Website: https://rohan-kshirsagar.netlify.app

# ROHAN KSHIRSAGAR

#### **Summary**

Software Developer having experience more than 1 year in Java and Spring Framework. Ability to work and communicate effectively with large and small teams in a fast-paced innovative and agile environment. Self motivated and ability to work effectively with minimal supervision to provide quality work with keen attention towards detail in pressure situations.

#### **Educations**

Lakehead University, Thunder Bay, Ontario, Canada Sep 2017-Dec 2019

Master's in Computer Science 3.3 GPA

Mumbai University, Mumbai, India Aug 2013-May 2016

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering 3.5 GPA

#### **Skills**

Programming Languages : (proficient): Java (familiar): C#, C++, PHP

Framework : (proficient): Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA and Hibernate

(familiar): Rest API, Spring Security

Web Development : HTML, CSS, React.js, JavaScript, Bootstrap and Thymeleaf

Databases : MySQL

Tools : Maven, JIRA, HPQC, Eclipse, Postman, STS

Operating Systems : Windows, Linux

Version Control : Git

Methodology : Waterfall Model, Agile

#### **Work Experience**

## APPLICATION PROGRAMMER ANALYST

**January 2020-Present** 

# Ministry of Education, CSC (Government of Canada), Toronto, Ontario, Canada.

- Received training on Spring Framework application and utilized that training for implementing reliable, reusable code for module features for new release.
- Solving the bugs from low to moderate level tickets assigned by testers on HPQC.
- Test and maintain the project code to ensure strong functionality and optimization.
- Practiced coding development environment using Jenkins and Git.

# COVID-19 PROJECT (APPLICATION THAT'S TRACKS COVID CASES ACROSS ALL ONTARIO REGISTERED SCHOOLS INCLUDING STAFF)

- Debugs and resolves low to high complexity software bugs with close direction from senior software developer.
- Participated in daily/weekly scrum meetings and closely followed agile development practices.

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

December 2016-July 2017

# The Coders, Mumbai, India

- Managed and maintained database by implementing insert, update, and delete queries on the data.
- Developed script to automate the removal of unusable data generated thus saving manual labour by 75%.
- Created Search filtration for making Search feature more flexible.
- Create technical documentation for reference and reporting.

#### **Projects**

#### STEGANORAGPHY WITH CRYPTOGRAPHY (C#)

- Objective of the project is to develop an applications that has a multilevel security with cryptography and steganography algorithm for multimedia files to ensure two level securities to our application and as well as maintaining the integrity of data.
- An extra level of security was applied using Parity bit on secret message before applying the AES encryption.
- And finally on encrypted message LSB algorithm was applied to embed the data into the Image.
- Supported data: Image, Audio, Video and Text.

# Portfolio Website <a href="https://rohan-kshirsagar.netlify.app">https://rohan-kshirsagar.netlify.app</a> (REACT JS)

- Designed and developed the Portfolio Website to have hands on skills and experience using React js.
- Gained the knowledge of React js by writing code from scratch by designing Navigation, body, footer, drawer etc.

• Made use of features like 'react-router-dom', props for navigation and passing data from component to another.

#### SENTIMENTAL ANALYSIS OF APPLICATION ON GOOGLE PLAYSTORE (JAVA)

- Provide features such Graphical representation of score, Summarization of comments and comparison of
  playstore score with sentimental score.
- Performed sentiment analysis on comments made on application to determine whether the app is good or average or bad.
- Data Preprocessing measures such as tokenization, elimination of stop words, lemmatization was applied on the train and test data.
- The data vectorization was achieved using the Library's Tokenizer class and then transferred to the LSTM model as an input.

#### MOBILE ENABLE CAMPUS WIFI SYSTEM (JAVA)

- The proposed system was developed with intention of College portal where student can access the application from any location.
- It supported features such as File Sharing, Post request for (Issuing library books, Notes), Fees payment Notification, College annual function post, Replacement for lecture and placing print job.

#### SMART CONTACT MANAGER, AWS HOSTING (JAVA, SPRING)

- Built an online portal/website where user can maintain the N number of contacts (Basically 1 to N mapping).
- A Registered user can search for contacts/user, can update the contacts and delete contact.
- An Email verification feature if password needed to reset.
- Gained Knowledge on AWS Hosting and Spring Security.

## WEB APPLICATION FOR HEALTH [DR.VIRTUAL] (C#)

- Built an online portal/website which connects remote patients to a doctor.
- The proposed system provides features such as predicting diseases based on symptoms, suggesting medication and specialist doctors and providing communication between patient and doctor.
- Statistical data was analyzed and used as an input for medication.
- Third party API was integrated to send notification between doctor and patient.

#### WEB APPLICATION FOR COURSE REGISTRATION (JAVA, SPRINGBOOT, REST API, REACT JS)

- Built an online course application for student where they can register for courses.
- Has a functionality of adding, deleting, updating and searching the courses.
- Leverage knowledge on Rest API and React Js.

#### Awards

## Mobile Enable Campus Wi-Fi System

2013 | MUMBAI, INDIA

- National Level Project Competition by M.S.B.T.E
- In association with M.S.B.T.E, IEEE Bombay section, SIEMENS and PCS Tech.